<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Christian information concerning these last times wherein all people may clearly see what prophesies the Holy Prophets prophesied of should come to pass, which of them is fulfilling and which is fulfilled, and how the lowest part of the great image that Daniel shewed to the King is now a breaking to pouder, and by whom, whereby people may see how very-near Antichrist or the great whore of Babylon is to her end : also some prophetical passages gathered out of Jacob Behme's works, who prophesied and gave them forth in the year 1623, concerning what should come to pass in these northern islands ... / wrinten [sic] in the fifth month by F.E.</title>
            <author>F. E. (Francis Ellington)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1664</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 39 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A39244</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E541</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R27165</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">09681681</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 09681681</idno>
            <idno type="VID">43978</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A39244)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 43978)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1330:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Christian information concerning these last times wherein all people may clearly see what prophesies the Holy Prophets prophesied of should come to pass, which of them is fulfilling and which is fulfilled, and how the lowest part of the great image that Daniel shewed to the King is now a breaking to pouder, and by whom, whereby people may see how very-near Antichrist or the great whore of Babylon is to her end : also some prophetical passages gathered out of Jacob Behme's works, who prophesied and gave them forth in the year 1623, concerning what should come to pass in these northern islands ... / wrinten [sic] in the fifth month by F.E.</title>
                  <author>F. E. (Francis Ellington)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1664.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bible --  Prophecies.</term>
               <term>Second Advent.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Prophecies.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:43978:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>Chriſtian Information Concerning theſe Laſt times.</p>
            <p>Wherein all people may clearly ſee what Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſies the holy <hi>Prophets</hi> propheſied of ſhould come to paſs: which of them is fulfilling, and which is fulfilled; and how the low<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt part of the great Image, that <hi>Daniel</hi> ſhew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to the King, is now a breaking to ponder, and by whom; whereby People may ſee, how very-near <hi>Antichriſt,</hi> or the great <hi>Whore of Babylon,</hi> is to her End.</p>
            <p>Alſo ſome prophetical Paſſages gathered out of <hi>Jacob Behme</hi>'s Works, who propheſied and gave them forth, in the year, 1623. Concerning what ſhould come to paſs in theſe <hi>Northern Iſlands;</hi> and as he then declared them, they are now come to paſs; and alſo what he ſaid concerning the <hi>Turk,</hi> what he was, what he ſhould do, and what ſhould at laſt become of him.</p>
            <p>Wrinten in the fifth Month, by <hi>F. E.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>Here is Wiſdom, let him that hath Wit, count the Number of the Beaſt, for its the number of a Man; and his Number is <hi>(all the nume<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Letters in the</hi> Roman <hi>Alphabet, being rightly placed thus;) MDCLXVI.</hi>
               <bibl>Revel. <hi>13.18.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the Year, 1664.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:43978:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:43978:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Chriſtian</hi> INFORMATION <hi>concerning theſe Laſt Times.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>CHriſt Jeſus, the Light of the World, was (as you may read, <hi>Mat.</hi> 16.) tempted with an hypocritical People, who deſired that he would ſhew them a ſign from hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven; but he anſwered and ſaid unto them, <hi>When it is evening, ye ſay, fair weather, for the skie is red; and in the morning, the day ſhall be tempeſtuous, for the skie is red and lowring: O ye hypocrites, ye can diſcern the face of the skie, and can ye not diſcern the ſigns of the times?</hi> O ye Rulers of this Nation of <hi>England,</hi> and the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple thereof, can ye as yet diſcern any more concerning the ſigns of the times, that you now live in, then thoſe Hypocrites did in the dayes by-paſt? can ye not at all diſcern what the Lord hath done, and what the Lord is bringing to paſs in this your day? is not our God working a Work in your day, and ſuch a Work as you will not believe though it be declared unto you? Nay, are not you covered with thick darkneſs, more than any age or gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of men that ever went before you? Have not you had the Writings of the holy Prophets, and of Chriſt and his Apoſtles, that have propheſied from the holy Spirit of the Lord; and they have left unto you upon record, what the Lord would bring to paſs in the latter dayes; and the Book is ſealed unto you yet; ſo that you will not (or cannot) read what is written therein? O all you that profeſs your ſelves Chriſtians, and ſay you own that which is written in the holy Scriptures of Truth, and yet are found at this day walking and acting clear contrary to that which is written in that which you own and profeſs, both Rulers, Prieſts &amp; People: will not the words that Chriſt hath left unto you upon record judge you all at the laſt day, who are found making void his Commands by your Precepts? is there not one Lawgiver, who is able to ſave and deſtroy, left you upon record? and ought not all mens Laws to be ſubordinate unto his Law? O conſider theſe things, for the Lord will ſuddenly ariſe againſt ſuch a People, that have deſtroyed (or made void) his righteous Law. O Nation of <hi>England,</hi> the Land of my Nativity, which way ſhall I take up a Lamentation for thee, and how do I mourn for thee, to ſee both
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:43978:3"/>Rulers, Prieſts and People, ſetting themſelves, like ſo many bri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and brambles, to prevent and ſtop the Work of the Lord, that he hath decreed ſhall now be brought to paſs in the Earth; and though the Scriptures, that you ſay you own, declare of ſuch a Work, as that <hi>the Lord will overthrow Babylon;</hi> and <hi>the Lamb and his Fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowers ſhall have the victory over the Dragon and his Followers,</hi> yet you will not believe, but ſet your ſelves, with all your power, againſt the Lord, and againſt his People; abuſing, and ſhamefully in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treating his faithful Prophets, whom he hath raiſed by his own Power, and that in your own borders firſt, to declare unto you his <hi>everlaſting Goſpel,</hi> that ſo you might be <hi>turned from darkneſs unto Light,</hi> and <hi>from the power of Satan unto God:</hi> And alſo they have, as righteous <hi>Noah</hi> did, declared unto you, that the Lord would ſuddenly bring a Deluge upon the world of ungodly men, if they did not ſuddenly repent, and turn from their wicked wayes. And this Meſſage of the King of Heaven, they have faithfully decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red through thy Streets, Citties and Markets, unto all thy Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants, as well unto thee, <hi>O King Charles</hi> (whom their God hath ſet upon thy Throne) as to the Begger that ſits upon the Dunghil; and in ſo doing, the Lord's Mercy hath been large unto you all, in that he hath faithfully warned you all by his Servants, the thing that muſt ſuddenly be fulfilled upon you: but have you done as the King of <hi>Nineveh</hi> did, with his People? or have you at all belie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved the report of the Lord's Servants? but have you not done as thoſe did in <hi>Zedekiahs</hi> day, both Rulers and People? <hi>Have you not done evil in the ſight of the Lord, and have not humbled your ſelues before him?</hi> 2 Chron. 36. have not all the chief of the Prieſts, and alſo of the People, treſpaſſed wonderfully according to all the Abominations of the Heathen, in teaching for Doctrines, mens Precepts? And hath not the Lord God of your Fathers, ſent to you by his Meſſengers (whom you in deriſion call <hi>Quakers</hi>) and they have faithfully declared his Meſſage unto you; And have not you <hi>mocked the Meſſengers of the Lord;</hi> and made a Decree that his Labourers ſhall no more labour in this his Vineyard? and you have deſpiſed their words, and miſuſed and impriſoned his Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets, whom he hath ſent, until the Lord's Wrath is riſen againſt you, and there will be no remedy; and will you, <hi>who are as Briars and Thorns, ſet your ſelves in battle-aray againſt the Lord, who is a con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuming Fire to all the workers of Iniquity,</hi> and whoſe day (that is near at hand) <hi>burns like an oven, and all the proud, and all that does
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:43978:3"/>wickedly, ſhall be as ſtubble, and the day that cometh ſhall burn them up, ſaith the Lord of Hoſts, and ſhall leave them neither root nor branch, Mal.</hi> 4.1. O fooliſh people, conſider theſe things, before it be too late, and <hi>ceaſe to do evil, and learn to do well;</hi> ſeek Judgement, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve the oppreſſed, judge the Fatherleſs, and defend the Wid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dows: but if you do not theſe things, but (on the contrary,) let your Decree ſtand, that will make many thouſands widdows, and thouſands fatherleſs; the Lord will never reaſon with you, but by his ſore Judgements he will overthrow you, and none ſhall be able to help you, ſaith the Lord God.</p>
            <p>For this the Lord hath commanded me to declare unto you, and alſo to his ſuffering Lambs, who ſuffers under your power at this day, that ſo you may be warned of the evil of your wayes, and his People may be comforted, <hi>that their day of deliverance draweth very near,</hi> that ſo they may ſtand with boldneſs this day of great tryal, not fearing what man can do unto them; for the Lord hath ſhewed unto me the ſigns of the time in which we live; and thoſe <hi>Viſions that were for an appointed time,</hi> ſhewed unto the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets of the Lord, <hi>Hab.</hi> 2.3. do now at laſt in this our day, <hi>ſpeak, and not lye;</hi> and though it tarryed, yet we have waited for it, and they are ſurely come, and muſt ſtay no longer.</p>
            <p>Now this I declare not unto you by only reading of the Hiſtory without me, hearing there that ſuch things are to come to paſs; but I declare of what the Lord hath wrought of his Work <hi>within me:</hi> And who ever judgeth of the times by no other thing than what he finds in the hiſtory without him, or by what he may at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain unto by the ſtars, or by the face of the heavens, without h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>m, ſuch a one can never know the ſigns of the times, but is one with the hypocritical Generation among whom he lives. And as the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>believing Jews, who had the Propheſies of Chriſt's being born among them, and the place where he ſhould be born, yet when he was born, according to the writings they had, they would not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve it was he, but perſecuted him, and put him to death: And as <hi>William Lilly</hi> in his Book, <hi>[Monarchy or no Monarchy]</hi> had a clear ſight by what he ſaw, and read without him, of the Lord's People that ſhould ariſe in this Nation, what manner of People they ſhould be, what they ſhould do, how they ſhould <hi>Convert People,</hi> which had been a thing but only talked of, and how they ſhould proſper, and he not at all witneſſing the thing, he declared of within him, but only what he ſaw <hi>by things</hi> without him, I ſay,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:43978:4"/>when thoſe people were brought forth, according to what he had declared, and in every thing agreeable, in Life, Converſation, and Doctrine, to what he had given forth; yet this man, as the unbelieving <hi>Jews,</hi> would not believe when they were come, that ſuch were the people he had propheſied of; but his Wife who minded the teaching of the Lord within her, and giving heed un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to that, ſhe could ſay of a truth, when thoſe people aroſe, that they were the People of the Lord that her Husband had before de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared of.</p>
            <p>Now <hi>all dear Friends</hi> and People every where, you may know that there was a time, after <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> had tranſgreſſed the Righteous Law of God, that the Lord in his love made a Promiſe unto them, <hi>that the Seed of the Woman ſhould break the Serpents head.</hi> While man lives in ſin and tranſgreſſion, this is not wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſed. And ſo according to the Doctrine of the Prieſts of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> who ſay (contrary to the Scripture and Book of Common-Prayer) that none ſhall ever be perfect, or freed from commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting ſin while on this ſide of the grave; and ſo denies this pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe of the Lord, in that the Seed of the Woman ſhall ever break the Serpents head; and ſo would make God a lyar, in not performing what he hath promiſed; but this promiſe through the Lords love many at this day can witneſs: and who witneſſeth this, their day of deliverance is come.</p>
            <p>After <hi>Moſes</hi> propheſied that <hi>the Lord ſhould raiſe them a Prophet like unto him, and him they ſhould hear in all things;</hi> And this Prophet is come, and the Lords People hear him, teaching in them, and are made willing to be ſubject unto his Laws, and Government. And becauſe they do ſo, therefore the Kings of the earth, and the Rulers, they take counſel againſt the Lord, and againſt his People, and would have them do things, contrary to the Law that this great Prophet, who is come, hath left them upon Record, to obſerve and do; and great penalties are laid upon them if they will not break his Righteous Law: and if that perſon muſt be cut off that will not hear this Prophet, what will be the portion of thoſe Rulers, that make Decrees, and Laws, to cauſe his Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teous Law to be broken, and perſecute thoſe that keep his Law? Conſider theſe things and repent. <hi>Ezekel</hi> 37. The Lord ſhewed him in a Viſion the True Seed of Spiritual <hi>Iſrael,</hi> which were re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſented by the dry bones, which lay ſcattered in the open fields, and lo he ſaw them to be very dry; and the Lord ſaid unto him,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:43978:4"/>
               <hi>Son of Man, Can theſe bones live?</hi> And the Prophet anſwered, <hi>Lord, thou knoweth.</hi> O my dear Friends, who lay with me in the open field, and who the Lord ſent, his faithful Servants, out of the <hi>North</hi> Countrey to propheſie upon us dry bones, and they did as the Lord commanded them, and ſaid unto us, Hear the Word of the Lord, <hi>Thus ſaith the Lord unto theſe dry bones, Behold I will cauſe breath to enter into you, and ye ſhall live, and I will lay ſinews upon you, and make fleſh grow upon you, and cover you with skin, and put breath into you, that ye may live, and ye ſhall know that I am the Lord.</hi> So the Lord's Prophets propheſied as he had com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded them; and as they propheſied, there was <hi>a noiſe,</hi> and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold there was <hi>a ſhaking,</hi> (or trembling) and at that time, thoſe that were not of the True Seed of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> ſeeing us tremble and quake at the Word of the Lord, they in ſcorn in that Day called us <hi>Quakers;</hi> then as they continued propheſying upon us, <hi>We dry bones came together, bone to his bone;</hi> This was the beginning of the Lord's Peoples Meetings, and therefore we cannot but meet to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, as many as the Lord ſhall move to make up a body, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding the Decrees of men would have us meet but to the Number of <hi>Four</hi> beſides the Houſhold, and ſo would have us to be a weak and infirm body, contrary to what the Lord hath joyned together to make up the body; <hi>but we cannot ſay to the eye, we have no need of thee, nor to the hand, we have no need of thee,</hi> but every Member is to be uſeful and helpful in his place, to the comfort of the body: and ſince we have come to witneſs this propheſie ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>filled in us, in this our day, our God hath not only knit our bones together with ſinews, whereby we are ſtrengthened one by ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and his love is ſhed abroad in our hearts, that makes fleſh to grow and cover theſe bones; but alſo he hath put his Spirit of Life into us, whereby we come to feel and taſte and handle of our God, and that makes us live out of the pleaſures, cuſtoms, faſhions and traditions of this world; and this Life that our God hath put into us, makes us to ſtand upon our feet, and we are become an exceeding great Army, having neither <hi>Sword</hi> nor <hi>Spear,</hi> but <hi>the Spirit of the Living God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now <hi>dear Friends,</hi> many thouſands of you, you know, are come with me hither, therefore fear not, for we are the people that this propheſie ſhall very ſhortly be fulfilled upon, notwithſtanding the Decrees of men to root us out, for none are of the True Seed of the houſe of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> but thoſe whom the Lord hath or ſhall make
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:43978:5"/>ſenſible of their dry bones condition, and that witneſs the Work of the Lord within them, and be not diſmayed, though you hear of <hi>Gog</hi> and <hi>Magog;</hi> (that is all who own not the Truth as it is in Jeſus,) riſing up and gathering themſelves againſt you, threatning to baniſh and to root out this Army, whom the Lord by his mighty power hath at this day raiſed up, according to <hi>Ezekiel</hi>'s propheſie; for if thou read the 38. and 39. chapters, thou ſhalt there ſee, <hi>who among the Nations ſhall be delivered from Gog and his Army,</hi> and who ſhall deliver them. Thou mayeſt read, that he ſhall over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come many people, and but one ſort of people ſhall be delivered from him, and they are ſuch who live without <hi>walled Towers,</hi> that are at reſt, and that dwell in ſafety; which dwell all without <hi>walls,</hi> and have neither <hi>Bars</hi> nor <hi>Gates,</hi> which are not of the <hi>Natio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Churches,</hi> which are the People that are gathered out of the Nations; theſe are they that the Lord will deliver, that have <hi>broken their Spears into Pruning-hooks, and their Swords into Sithes, that have learned to War no more.</hi> And all you people of what Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion ſoever, that cannot witneſs theſe things in your own parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culars, as being truly called from the dry bones ſtate, and that have not <hi>Salvation for Walls and Bullwarks,</hi> which are not yet re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deemed from a War-like Spirit, and that are not come to witneſs Chriſts Kingdom come, which is not of this world, who are not yet entred into your Reſt, Chriſt Jeſus the Light, in whom is ſafety, and no where elſe, and that are not as yet gathered out of the Nations, but are yet with them in their Wayes, Worſhips, Faſhions and Cuſtoms, you muſt all fall under <hi>Gog</hi> and his Army, and as ſoon as you are all overcome by him, then will the Lord overthrow <hi>Gog</hi> with all his Army; and this is ſuddenly to come to paſs, and the Lord will perform it for his Seeds ſake.</p>
            <p>And that this propheſie hath not been in former time fulfilled, the Prophet ſaith in the 38. <hi>Chap.</hi> and 16. <hi>verſe, it ſhall be in the latter dayes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And for the comfort of the Suffering Seed of the Lord this day, this I am to declare unto you, <hi>That this is the time that</hi> Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niel's <hi>Propheſie is now to be fulfilled,</hi> (though it hath been long a fulfilling) for we are in that time, that <hi>Daniel</hi> ſaw, <hi>Chap.</hi> 2.41, 42, 43, 44. And the Lord hath by his Power cut us out of the Mountain without hands, for every hand hath been againſt us, ever ſince he cut us forth; <hi>And this ſtone cut out without hands, doth grow, and it muſt, and will, fill the whole earth,</hi> and now it is
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:43978:5"/>at work to <hi>break in pieces</hi> the latter part of <hi>the great Image, whoſe feet and toes were part Iron, and part Clay;</hi> ſo the Kingdom is partly ſtrong, and partly broken; and as this part of the Image is a mixture of Clay and Iron, ſo hath Anti-Chriſt's Kingdom, ming<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led themſelves with the Seed of men, ſome in one form, and ſome in another form, ſo that they cannot joyn together, but <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>piſts</hi> againſt <hi>Epiſcopal,</hi> and <hi>Epiſcopal</hi> againſt <hi>Presbytery,</hi> and <hi>Pres<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bytery</hi> and all others, againſt thoſe who are cut out of the Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain without hands: <hi>But in the dayes of theſe Kings, hath the God of Heaven ſet up a Kingdom, which ſhall never be deſtroyed,</hi> (there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore fear not) <hi>and this Kingdom ſhall not be given unto another people, but it ſhall break and deſtroy all theſe Kingdoms, and it ſhall ſtand for ever;</hi> and it will be as hard a work for the men of this Generation, to remove this Mountain whom the Lord hath cut out without hands, and to carry it away from this Iſland beyond the Seas, as to remove the greateſt Mountain upon the earth, and to carry it to the place they have decreed; for if the Decree of the Lord be, that it <hi>muſt fill the whole earth,</hi> where will vain man have a place to put it; Therefore I ſay unto the men of this Generation, who make Laws and Decrees, againſt the Laws and Decrees of the Lord, as once <hi>Balaam</hi> ſaid to <hi>Balaak</hi> and his Princes, <hi>Hearken ye Kings, and give ear ye Princes, God is not as man that he ſhould lie, neither as the ſon of man that he ſhould repent; hath he ſaid, and ſhall he not do it?</hi> Hath he ſaid that <hi>Babylon ſhall fall</hi> and be broken, and that the Image which <hi>Daniel</hi> ſaw, ſhould be broken by the ſtone cut out of the Mountain without hands, and that in the latter dayes, and that thoſe people ſhall be delivered from the Sword, that cannot fight with a Carnal Sword, but are redeemed out of it; and hath he ſaid it, and will he not do it? and hath he ſpoken by his Servants the Prophets, what he will bring to paſs in the earth, and ſhall he not accompliſh it? Hath he ſpoke by <hi>Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>remiah</hi> his Faithful Prophet, <hi>Jer.</hi> 23. <hi>Behold the dayes come, ſaith the Lord, that I will raiſe unto</hi> David <hi>a Righteous Branch, and a King ſhall reign and proſper, and ſhall execute Judgement and Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, in the earth, in his dayes</hi> Judah <hi>ſhall be ſaved, and</hi> Iſrael <hi>ſhall dwell ſafely; and this is the Name whereby they ſhall call him, The Lord our Righteouſneſs;</hi> Therefore behold the dayes come ſaith the Lord, that <hi>they ſhall no more ſay, the Lord liveth that brought up the Children of</hi> Iſrael <hi>out of the Land of</hi> Egypt, (Mark) that de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liverance was Great; but one is coming near that ſhall be greater,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:43978:6"/>unto which the leſſer muſt give place; and in this our day we wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs it a fulfilling, and we can in meaſure ſay already, <hi>The Lord liveth, which brought up and led the Seed of the Houſe of</hi> Iſrael <hi>out of the</hi> North <hi>Countrey,</hi> (mark that) <hi>and from all Countries where they were ſcattered, and they ſhall dwell in their own Land;</hi> There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore lift up your heads all you who are come hither, for delive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance is near unto you; for now is the Lord fulfilling of this Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie upon his people, and in this <hi>Northern</hi> Iſland hath he began his great work, in bringing up his Seed, and leading out of the <hi>North</hi> Countrey, and from all other Countries where they have been ſcattered; for now is the Woman ſpoken of in the <hi>Revelati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on,</hi> returning out of the Wilderneſs, whom the Dragon caſt forth floods after, but the Man-Child was caught up to God, but the Dragon made great War, and hath perſecuted her Seed; but now is the everlaſting Goſpel Preached, by the Angel that flew in the midſt of Heaven; And the next tydings will be, <hi>Babylon is fallen, for ſhe made all the Nations drink of the Wine of the Wrath of her Fornication,</hi> (mark that) ſhe forced the Nations to drink of her Wine, of the Cup of Fornication; but the Kings of the Earth were not forced to drink of her Cup, but they drank it freely from her hand, and were ſo much in love with her, that they joyned with her, and committed Fornication freely with her; and the Merchants of the earth waxed rich, of the abundance of her plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures; but now the dayes of her mourning is come, and coming upon her, and the dark night of Apoſtacy, in which ſhe hath drunk the blood of the Saints, is near come to an end; <hi>And the tydings out of the</hi> Eaſt, <hi>and out of the</hi> North, <hi>doth now ſore trouble her,</hi> and what the Lord ſpake through that Faithful Servant of his <hi>Jacob Behme,</hi> in the Year 1623. is now near to be fulfilled, as may be read in his Book, entituled, <hi>A Chriſtian Information concerning the Laſt Times,</hi> wherein he ſaith, <hi>The Oriental Beaſt getteth an Humane heart and face, viz.</hi> that is, <hi>The</hi> Turk <hi>ſhall turn a true Chriſtian; but before this comes to paſs, while he is a beaſt, he ſhall help to tear down the Tower of</hi> Babel <hi>with his Claws; for this end hath the Lord raiſed him, that ſo the tydings out of the</hi> Eaſt <hi>ſhould trouble</hi> Babel: And likewiſe the tydings out of the <hi>North</hi> doth at this day migh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tily trouble the <hi>Inhabitants</hi> of <hi>Babel</hi> to hear <hi>that the Lord hath raiſed his Seed in the</hi> North <hi>Countrey;</hi> and now they beſtir themſelves, and they would have them driven out of this <hi>North</hi> Countrey by all means, and if ever they ſhall return again within ſeven years,
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:43978:6"/>then they muſt die without benefit of their Clergie; It ſeems the Clergie will neither ſave their lives, nor have pitty of them, nor pray for them. O hard-hearted Generation of Clergy men, will you not pray for Enemies, nor have pitty on them, but give the Lambs of Chriſt, if they come amongſt you, up to the ſlaugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter? Are you like unto <hi>Chriſt, who came not to deſtroy mens lives, but to ſave mens lives?</hi> Though you have <hi>Horns like the Lamb,</hi> yet you <hi>ſpeak like the Dragon;</hi> and you appear to be <hi>Wolves in Sheeps skins,</hi> that are thus minded.</p>
            <p>But hear further what this <hi>German</hi> Author ſaid, further he ſaid, <hi>In the darkneſs of the</hi> North <hi>ariſeth a Sun, which taketh its Light from the ſenſualiſh properties of the Nature of all Beings, from the former expreſſed Word; and this is a Wonder, at which all Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons rejoyce;</hi> This is fulfilled in this Nation.</p>
            <p>Alſo he ſaith, <hi>An Eagle (viz. the Emperor of</hi> Germany) <hi>hath hatched young Lyons in his Neſt, and brought them Prey, till they have grown great, hoping that they would again bring their Prey to him; but they have forgotten that, and taken the Eagles Neſt, and pluck off his Feathers, and in unfaithfulneſs bit off his Claws, ſo that he can fetch no more Prey, though he ſhould ſtarve for hunger.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Alſo he ſaith concerning the <hi>Turk, That he ſhould very eaſily come to the</hi> Rhine <hi>ſtream, which now the</hi> Turk <hi>at this time is near,</hi> being a River that runs through the heart of <hi>Germany, where</hi> (ſaith he) <hi>then the great overthrow of the Children of</hi> Babilon <hi>may come to paſs, where two great Rods ſhall appear, the one by War, the other by Mortality, in which</hi> Babel <hi>ſhall be ruined, ſaith the Spirit of the Lord, in all thoſe who have propheſied before us.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Further he ſaith, <hi>A Lilly bloſſometh to you ye</hi> Northern <hi>Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries, if you deſtroy it not with the Sectarian contention of the Learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, then it will become a great Tree among you; but if you ſhall ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther contend then to know the True God, then the Ray paſſeth by, and hiteth only ſome; and then afterwards you ſhall be forced to draw water for the thirſt of your Souls, among ſtrange Nations.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And as it was propheſied of by this Prophet of the Lord, ſo the Lord hath brought it to paſs, and the Lilly is bloſſomed in this Iſland, and the Sectarian Contention of the Learned, have done what they can to overthrow this Lilly: as witneſs of the publick Teachers in theſe Nations, that have Writ and Printed againſt the Lilly; as is to be ſeen in the Book put forth by <hi>George Fox,</hi> and Intituled, <hi>The great Myſtery of the Whore unfolded,</hi> wherein 197.
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:43978:7"/>of the publick Teachers are confuted, and their Errors condemned, and their mouths ſtopped to their ſhame for ever, and ſo the Lil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly is become a great Tree in this Nation; Praiſes to the Lord for ever.</p>
            <p>And for all you who do not witneſs the Lilly brought forth in you, but are ready to ask what this Lilly is, the Author tells you in his Book what it is, and how you may know it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Lilly</hi> (ſaith he) <hi>will not be found in ſtrife or Wars, but in a friendly, humble, loving Spirit, together with good ſound Reaſon; this will diſpel and drive away the ſmoak of the Devil, and flouriſh in its tim<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, to the overthrowing of</hi> Babel, <hi>and the building up of</hi> Zion.</p>
            <p>Alſo in his book he ſaith, <hi>That the Turks, after they have tared down the Tower of Babel as a Beaſt, with their claws, and given thoſe People and Nations Blood to drink, that have drunk the Blood of the Saints and Martyrs of Jeſus, then they ſhall</hi> (ſaith he) <hi>come in with great joy and great humility, unto Abraham,</hi> viz. <hi>that is to ſay, unto Chriſt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And (he ſaith) <hi>They ſhall not come in, in the form of the Babyloni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal formal, litteral Chriſtendom, in their invented and contrived Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, which are only verbal, outſide Chriſtians, ſo that a Teſtimony, and ſome outward footſteps of Chriſt and his Kingdom, have ſtill continued upon the Earth, but they ſhall be born in ſpirit and power, for they are the loſt Son, that is wandred away from the Father, and is be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come the Swineherd.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>But when the Angel ſhall bid them return, they come in the humi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity of the loſt Son, returning to the Father, where then the great Joy ſhall be kept by Chriſt and his Angels, that the dead is made alive, and the loſt is again found, and the true golden Jubal year of the mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage of the Lamb ariſeth up among them.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And albeit Chriſtendom, the Elder Brother (who hath continued in the Letter) doth grumble at it, in reſpect of the different form, that he hath made to himſelf (for the moſt part for his belly and honour) yet they are not moved at it, they are merry with the Father.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And they are the two Sons: to one whereof the Father ſaid, Go and do this; and he ſaid, Yea, but did it not: and to the other Son (which is the Turk) Do this, and he ſaid, No, but did it, which doth ſo highly advance (and magnifie) the Turks in the Kingdom of Nature, which the blind Chriſtian World doth not underſtand: and though Chriſten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom calls them by the name of Infidels and Unbelievers, yet,</hi> ſaith, he
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:43978:7"/>
               <hi>they are both alike while the one lives like the other.</hi> And as it is written, <hi>Gal.</hi> 4.29. <hi>He that is born after the fleſh, perſecutes him that is born after the ſpirit.</hi> So all Perſecutors, may ſee what ſtock they proceed from (the bond woman) who muſt be caſt out, and the time draws very near; for he, who ever he be, that perſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutes his brother, is in <hi>Cains</hi> way, and is a Murtherer; for when there were but only <hi>Cain</hi> and <hi>Abel</hi> born in the Earth, yet he that was the Perſecutor, would have an uniformity in Religion, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe his Brother would not offer ſacrifice as he did, he was wrath with him, and ſlew his brother, and the reaſon was, becauſe the one Sacrifice was accepted with the Lord, and the Perſecutors was not.</p>
            <p>And there is no other reaſon or cauſe at this day, that men are ſo mad to perſecute, to baniſh, kill &amp; impriſon their brethren, becauſe they cannot worſhip as thoſe do, who teach for Doctrine Mens Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepts: and by their ſo doing, they find no acceptance with the Lord; and this makes their countenance change, and they grow in wrath, and make cruel Laws againſt their Brethren, who worſhip God in Spirit &amp; in Truth, and whoſe worſhip is accepted of the Lord; but as it was with their firſt father <hi>Cain,</hi> who was the firſt perſecutor, he <hi>became a fugitive and a vagabond upon the earth,</hi> and the Lord ſet a mark upon him. So let all Perſecutors in this age, take notice of this one thing, That God hath in all Ages and Generations, pun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſhed this Sin of <hi>Perſecution,</hi> with one and the ſame Judgement, let it be found in whom it will, as Scripture at large do ſhew, and Hiſtories make mention; and the puniſhment was this, <hi>Their houſes was left unto them deſolate.</hi> See Mat. 23.37, 38. <hi>O Jeruſalem, Jeruſalem, thou that killeſt the Prophets, and ſtoneſt them that were ſent unto thee, how often would I have gathered thee, but ye would not,</hi> viz. <hi>Behold</hi> (ſaith Chriſt) <hi>your habitation ſhall be left unto you deſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>late.</hi> And if Perſecutors in this Age were not blind, they might reade, the Judgement of the Lord that have followed Perſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors in this particular, upon thoſe that are gone before them; for as man lets Envy into his heart, which is the ground of Murther and Perſecution, it eats out all good in him, and makes his heart deſolate of all good Motions of the Spirit of the Lord, ſo it is without: Peſecutors by that ſin, diſpoſes themſelves at laſt, and the Lord drives them from their habitation without; for all Perſecutors are all unreaſonable men, and ever were: for if I ſhould ask a <hi>King, Parliament</hi> or <hi>Council,</hi> that make Laws to
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:43978:8"/>force all other People to worſhip in that Manner, Form, Time and Place as they ſhall preſcribe, and if I be not convinced in my own Conſcience, that their way is right, and agreeable to the true Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip of God, which is in Spirit &amp; in Truth, and if I ſhould worſhip in their way, I ſhould ſin againſt God, and againſt mine own Conſcience, then if I ask that <hi>King, Parliament</hi> or <hi>Council,</hi> if they will undertake at the laſt day in my behalf <hi>(when God ſhall judge the Secrets of all hearts by Jeſus Chriſt)</hi> and will then keep me from the Eternal Puniſhment, that muſt be fulfilled upon all thoſe that worſhip God after mens Precepts, and contrary to that meaſure of Light he hath given me to profit and worſhip withal, dare any <hi>King, Parliament</hi> or <hi>Council</hi> give me any aſſurance that they will do it for me? If they ſhould ſay they would, yet I could not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve them, that they were able, or that they can ſave their own ſouls; neither can I believe that there is any <hi>reſpect of perſons with God,</hi> but <hi>Kings</hi> as well as others, <hi>muſt appear naked and bare before the Lord,</hi> and <hi>every one ſhall receive according to the things done in the body, whether good or evil;</hi> and alſo I read, <hi>that Tophet is prepared for the King as well as for the Beggar:</hi> Therefore ſeeing the <hi>King</hi> cannot ſave my ſoul, is it not an unreaſonable thing, that he ſhould force me to deſtroy my own Soul? Beſides, the <hi>King</hi> is not <hi>that great Prophet that we are to hear in all things,</hi> but ſhould be ſervant to that great Prophet: for <hi>Daniel</hi> and the three Children could not worſhip according to the Law of the King, and were juſtified in their ſo doing; as we may read, <hi>Dan.</hi> 3.18.</p>
            <p>Now ſeeing it is ſo, let all that fear the Lord, endeavour to keep their Conſcience clean and void of offence, both towards God and towards man, what ever we ſuffer under the hands of wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and unreaſonable men; for the time is near, that <hi>God will lift up his hand for his People, to deliver them after the manner of Egypt:</hi> And if the Lord ſhould ſuffer any of us to be baniſhed for his Truth ſake, from the Land of our Nativity, I know the Lord would give us favour in the ſight of the People firſt, as he hath done already, and we ſhould get much of their love with us, which is their beſt <hi>Jewels;</hi> and <hi>though it be midnight now, yet but few Dogs bark at us as they have done formerly;</hi> for the Lord's Truth doth begin to be of good report in this Nation, and few are the num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of Perſecutors now, as hath been formerly: (and as God ſet a mark upon <hi>Cain</hi> for perſecuting his Brother, ſo all men now that are God-like minded, and all that God hath given a ſpirit of mode<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:43978:8"/>unto, they mark all that are Perſecutors now; and who<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever he be that now is a Perſecutor, he is as much marked, as he that is a thief, and ſteals from his neighbour, the one being led by the ſpirit of covetouſneſs, and the other by a murtherous ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of envy, and both of the Devil.) And the greateſt part of men, are much moderated as to thoſe called <hi>Quakers,</hi> whereby I ſee that <hi>Babylon falls apace; for where moderation is, the Lord is near at hand,</hi> and the Devil hath now but a ſhort time, which makes him rage the more; for we live in theſe dayes, wherein Scripture-Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſies are fulfilled, and the Antient Viſions do now ſpeak, and we know what times we live in; and our God hath given us of his <hi>Light, Life,</hi> and <hi>Power,</hi> and hath called us to be of <hi>the Firſt Fruits unto the Lamb,</hi> and to be of that Number that muſt break in pieces the great Image, and now at laſt to ingage with the Lamb, to fight with the Dragon, and his Followers, which will be the laſt battel: for as the Lord hath been pleaſed to raiſe his Seed, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording as his Servants have foretold, and Scriptures have decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, in this Northren Iſland firſt, and from hence hath ſent his faithful Servants, in theſe late years, to the outmoſt parts of the Earth, to preach his <hi>Everlaſting Goſpel</hi> to the ſons of men, and the Lord's Work hath proſpered in their hands; <hi>ſo certainly as he hath begun his great work in this Iſland, ſo the Lord will finiſh it in this Iſland, and Antichriſt ſhall have his mortal blow in this Iſland firſt,</hi> whereby all <hi>Nations</hi> that hear of it, <hi>their hearts ſhall be ſtruck with fear, to hear what the mighty God hath done for his poor afflicted Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple in</hi> England. And the Servant of the Lord, <hi>J. S.</hi> hath decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red there ſhall be <hi>ſuch a day of deliverance, as the like was never be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it, nor never any ſhall be after it;</hi> and all Friends are to ſtand ſtill, for there is our ſtrength to ſtand ſtill, and to wait upon our God, out of our thoughts, reaſonings, and conſultations, and all keep in the Faith, for by that we ſhall conquer all our Enemies, both within and without, <hi>Heb.</hi> 11.1. for that's our ground <hi>of things hoped for, &amp; the evidence of things not ſeen.</hi> And Friends, this I declare, that I perceive ſuch a Faith that the Lord hath begot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten in his deſpiſed People called <hi>Quakers,</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> that fear not Baniſhment, no, nor death it ſelf; and this I find is begotten in thouſands that cannot ſpeak much for Truth, but they have Faith to ſuffer for Truth if the Lord calls them to it, whereby it is evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent they ſhall have at laſt the victory, and ſhall be ſaved in the Ark, the Light: which that was but a figure of, that ſaved <hi>Noah</hi>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:43978:9"/>and his family from drowning in the waters; and as the old world mocked <hi>Noah,</hi> and would not believe that the Ark would ſave him, ſo hath this Age mocked the People of the Lord, for believing in ſo low a thing as the Light, they ſay is. But the Lord hath ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a Flood to ariſe in this <hi>Nation,</hi> that hath well-nigh fetched off all the <hi>higheſt Profeſſions</hi> in <hi>England;</hi> though they have flown from Mountain to Hill, yet the Flood <hi>hath ariſen, and will ariſe,</hi> to fetch them all off: but all thoſe that abide in the Ark, the Light, ſhall flote upon the top of the Waters, and ſhall be ſafe, until the Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters are abated; wherein a New Earth ſhall appear, in which ſhall dwell Righteouſneſs.</p>
            <p>So all Friends who believe in the Ark, and dwell in it, <hi>keep to the Word of his Patience,</hi> and then your belief will not cauſe you to make haſte, for the Lord in his good time will perform what is here written, to the renown of you his ſuffering Seed for ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>more.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Written on <date>the 11. day of the 5th Month, 1664.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>F. E.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:43978:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
